I am aware that I am inhaling, I am aware that I am exhaling, I am following my
我觉知我吸气，我觉知我呼气，我就是我的
breath, I become aware of my body, I relax my body, I generate
呼吸，我觉知我的身体，我放松我的身体，我生起
a feeling of joy, I generate a feeling of happiness in
喜悦感，我生起幸福感在
the present.
当下。
I become aware of my pain, I embrace my pain, I take care of it.
我觉知我的疼痛，我拥抱我的疼痛，我照顾它。
It's important to have good motivation when you're going to start meditating.
当你开始冥想时，拥有良好的动机很重要。
will present you with obstacles. The first obstacle you
会给你带来障碍。你将遇到的第一个障碍
will encounter is laziness. It will
就是懒惰。它会
bring you a second subtlety, which is called active laziness. I was doing a
再给你带来第二种微妙之处，这就是所谓的积极性懒惰。我做了很多
lot of things except going to meditate. A third laziness that still arises is
事情，除了去冥想。第三种懒惰再次出现，那就是
giving up. But
放弃。但是
then you tell yourself no, ultimately it's not for me. The antidote
这时你对自己说不，最终这不适合我。解药是
is to find a just motivation.
找到一个正确的动机。
This motivation must be
这个动机必须是
not only for you, but also for others.
不仅为了你自己，也为了他人。
The second real obstacle you will encounter,
你将遇到的第二个真正障碍是，
is that when you learn to meditate,
当你学习冥想时，
initially, there is a methodology in learning.
一开始，学习中会有一个方法论。
The obstacle you will encounter is the complete forgetting of what needs to be done.
你将遇到的障碍是完全忘记该做什么。
At one point, I was meditating,
在某个时候，我正在冥想，
well, I thought I was meditating,
或者说，我以为我在冥想，
I was sitting there, ultimately, I was dreaming quite a bit.
我坐在那里，结果，我只是在做白日梦。
I understood that meditation is a training of the mind.
我明白了冥想是心智的训练。
It comes from a very ancient etymology that means...
它来自一个非常古老的词源，意思是...
Truly learning to discover one's own functioning.
真正学会发现自己的运作方式。
You're not always well when you meditate, but that's okay.
当你冥想时，你并非总是感觉良好，但这没关系。
I learn to recognize, to train my mind.
我学习识别，训练我的心智。
And the antidote, which I think is very interesting for us in the practice of meditation,
而解药，我认为对我们冥想练习来说非常有趣的是，
is attention, it's mindfulness.
是专注，是正念。
Discovering this energy that is in your mind, this energy that is concentration,
发现你心智中的这种能量，这种集中注意力的能量，
and which will gradually open you to another energy which is the deep vision of things.
并逐渐开启你对事物的深层洞察这种能量。
But you have to go little by little.
但这需要循序渐进。
It's like when you enter a space or on the walls.
这就像你进入一个空间，墙壁上。
There are secrets that can be revealed.
有一些秘密可以被揭示。
I enter with a candle, and the candle is your mind.
我带着一支蜡烛进去，这支蜡烛就是你的心智。
Initially, the candle moves like this, which means there's not really any brightness.
最初，蜡烛的火焰会这样摇曳，这意味着并没有真正的光亮。
But if through the practice of your meditation, the base, you learn to completely stabilize the flame,
但如果你通过冥想练习，从基础开始，学会完全稳定火焰，
a kind of luminous halo appears, a kind of clarity emerges.
就会出现一种光晕，一种清晰度会显现出来。
Well, it's a bit the same thing.
这也是同样的道理。
If you really manage to stabilize your mind, all of a sudden you will perceive a kind of
如果你真的能够稳定你的心智，突然间你就会感知到一种
luminous clarity.
光明的清晰度。
that appears in one's mind. This clarity leads you to deep vision.
出现在你的心智中。这种清晰度会引导你走向深层洞察。
You have to learn
你需要学习
to stabilize the mind because it's a whole work of stabilization. So
如何稳定心智，因为这是一个完整的稳定化过程。所以
it's learning
这就是学习
to develop this clarity of mind first through the energy of mindfulness,
如何发展这种心智的清晰度，首先通过正念的能量，
the energy of concentration and the energy of deep vision.
专注的能量，以及深层洞察的能量。
You have
你需要
to train. Everyone can have access to this.
练习。每个人都可以获得这种能力。